studocu.com 2019-12-06

# Privacy Policy - StuDocu

## 1.      Responsible person and contact details

We offer an online platform (www.studeersnel.nl and www.studocu.com, hereinafter: “StuDocu/Studeersnel”), where users can exchange study materials. We process personal details in the context of these activities. We respect your privacy, handle your personal data carefully in accordance with the General Data Privacy Regulation.

This privacy statement applies to the processing of personal details of all users and visitors of the websites: www.studeersnel.nl and www.studocu.com.

The contact for the processing of personal details is StudeerSnel B.V., located at the Keizersgracht, 1016 GC Amsterdam (registration number of Chamber of Commerce: 56829787). If you have questions about or comments on this privacy statement, please contact privacy@studocu.com.

We may change this privacy statement from time to time. When we publish a modified version, we clearly show this on our websites. On this page you always find the most recent version of our privacy statement.

## 2.     Processing of personal details

Personal data is all types of data that can be traceable to you as an individual, including your name, e-mail address and course of study, as well as your social media profile and your IP address.

We process your personal data when you use our services as described in our terms of use, for example when you upload documents via our website without an account or when you register to create an account to make use of different functions of our website. Some personal details are mandatory to provide because they are necessary to offer our services, other data is optional to fill in. You can always change or delete voluntary entered personal data using your own account.

In the following, we explain for each section why we process personal data, what personal data this can be and on what legal basis we do this.

Later in this privacy statement we explain with whom we share your personal data, where and how we store your data, how long we keep the personal data, what rights you have with regard to your personal data and how you can exercise these rights.

### 2.1.    Use of website and cookies

When you visit our websites, small text files are stored on your computer, smart phone or other device. These files are called “cookies”. Cookies help us with having function, analyze and personalize the website. For detailed information about the use of cookies and similar techniques, see also our cookie statement.

### 2.2.   Uploading documents without an account

If you want to upload documents immediately without creating an account, we may process your personal data. Your data may, for example, be visible in the title of the document you are uploading, the description of the document and the contents of the document may contain personal details. We want to point out that you can choose to make your uploaded documents anonymous by not giving any recognizable data to these documents. This way, you can change the name of the document and delete names in the document itself.

We process the following personal data from you:

  * IP address
  * Details about you that may be in the title, description or content of the document

We process this personal data for the following purposes:

  1. To give you access to our platform;
  2. To be able to exchange documents with fellow students;
  3. For analysis of the user behavior.

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data for purposes (1) and (2) is the implementation of an agreement with you (as specified in our terms of use) and a legitimate interest to perform our services properly when you choose to use personal data to be part of the documents you are uploading. The legal basis for purpose (3) is our legitimate interest in making our platform work as optimally as possible and to improve our services to users.

### 2.3.   Creating an account

When you register to create an account, it is necessary to process a number of your personal data. You can register yourself by entering your name and e-mail address and by inventing an account and you can register via your account on Facebook or Google+. In that case, we process the personal data that is linked to your social media profile, depending on the privacy settings that you use there.

We process the following data for you:

  * First and last name
  * Automatically generated initials based on your first and last name (for example ‘JD’)
  * Profile photo or image (optional)
  * E-mail address (this is only visible for StuDocu/StudeerSnel, not for fellow students)
  * University
  * Start date of study
  * Field of study
  * Facebook or Google+ profile (gender, email, first and last name) (optional)
  * IP address

We process this personal data for the following purposes:

  1. To give you access to our platform;
  2. To enrich your account with information about the use of our platform;
  3. To show your data (if you wish without your name) to fellow students when they use your documents or when you post a comment;
  4. To allow you to log in easily via your social media accounts at Facebook and Google+;
  5. To inform you about the content on your website that you have viewed.

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data for purpose (1) and (4) is the implementation of an agreement with you (as specified in our terms of use). With regard to the purposes (2), (3) and (5), we base ourselves on a legitimate interest to keep you informed of updates via, for example, your dashboard or e-mail, to analyze the usage to improve our service to users.

We would like to point out that when you use the services of Facebook or Google+ through our platform, these parties also gain access to some of your personal data on our platform. These external parties apply their own terms of use and privacy conditions. We advise you to read these conditions carefully. StuDocu/StudeerSnel is not responsible for this and does not have control over this.

### 2.4.    Using our platform

When you use our platform, you can search, upload and download documents, to make content available by transferring it to us (whether or not for a fee) and to respond to fellow students. For this, it is necessary to process a number of personal data, which we link to your account.

When you upload documents, you may also process personal data that is part of that document. For example, your data may be visible in the title of the document you are uploading, the description of the document and the content of the document may contain personal data. We would like to point out that you can choose yourself to make your uploaded documents anonymous by not giving any recognizable data to these documents. This way, you can change the name of the document and delete names in the document itself.

Your personal details are visible to other students in a public profile on our platform. You can choose to anonymously share documents with fellow students. In that case your document will not be shown in your public profile.

When you respond to documents and messages from fellow students, your first name is shown, which is visible to other students.

The following personal data is processed when you use our platform:

  * Number of points earned in the current and previous month
  * Numbers of lots
  * Number of fellow students that you have helped: your impact
  * Level
  * Uploaded documents: uploads, upvotes/downvotes and reactions on it from fellow students
  * Statistics
  * Books that you read and courses you follow
  * Reported documents: ‘I cannot open this document;’ ‘The description of this document is wrong; ’This document belongs to another subject or book;’ ‘Otherwise: it is an open text.’
  * Transferred content
  * Payment details, including the amount of compensation you received from us and your  
PayPal account.

We process this personal details for the following purposes:

  1. To display your activities in an overview in your profile
  2. To publish documents on the platform and to make it possible to exchange documents with fellow students
  3. To assess documents
  4. To show which documents a user has shared
  5. The higher ranking of documents that have been better assessed
  6. The payment of the agreed fee

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data for the purposes (1), (2) and (6) is the execution of an agreement with you (as specified in our terms of use). For the purposes (3), (4) and (5) we base ourselves on a legitimate interest to offer the user the best possible content.

### 2.5.   E-mail notifications and marketing e-mails

We send e-mails to users who have created an account. It concerns the following types of e-mails:

  * Weekly updates on new documents that have been uploaded to the courses you follow;
  * Tips and offers based on your use of StuDocu/StudeerSnel about, for example, new study tools;
  * Updates on Business Courses, Inhouse days and other interesting options that you can put on your CV;
  * Updates from our other services, for example exam trainings, namely;
  * Updates about new features or important changes on the website, up to 6 times a year.

The following personal data is processed for this:

  * Your e-mail address
  * First name
  * The content you have viewed from your profile.
  * The courses you follow

We process this personal data for the following purposes:

  1. To inform you about our own services (including the activation of your account, confirmation of your payment, etc.).
  2. To send messages with relevant information about updates within the subjects and books you have viewed.
  3. To inform you about other services, from other parties, including exam trainings.

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data for purpose (1) is our legitimate interest to keep you informed of offers and interesting messages about our platform and to send personalized messages that match the content you have viewed. We ask your permission for the purposes (2) and (3). You can withdraw this permission at any time. You can unsubscribe from e-mails by clicking on ‘unsubscribe’ at the bottom of every e-mail from us or by changing your preferences in your account settings. When you unsubscribe, StuDocu/StudeerSnel advises you to regularly monitor the platform or social media for new offers.

### 2.6.   Help center

If you have a question for us, you can contact our help center. You can send us a message via a web form. It is necessary to process the following personal data from you:

  * Name
  * E-mail address
  * Open text field with your question or message to us

We process this personal data for the following purposes:

  1. Answering your question or responding to your message
  2. Contact you as part of the processing of your question
  3. Analyzing the most common questions to improve the service

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data for purposes (1) and (2) is the execution of an agreement with you: answering your question or responding to your message and for purpose (3) our legitimate interest in improving the service.

## 3.     Automated decision making and profiling

We can use technologies that are considered automated decision-making or profiling. We do not take automated decisions about you that have a material effect on you or affect you to a significant degree, unless taking such a decision is necessary as part of an agreement we have with you, or if we have your consent or if we are legally obliged to use such technologies.

## 4.     Sharing your personal data

### 4.1.   Sharing internally

StuDocu/StudeerSnel shares your personal details internally only with employees who are authorized to have access to your details when this is necessary for their work.

### 4.2.   Outsourcing work and collaborating with partners

In addition, as part of the outsourcing of certain activities, we may share personal data with external parties, so called processors, with whom we have concluded processing agreements and who may not use your data for their own purposes. Some external parties are responsible for the processing of your personal data, for example if you create an account there (e.g. Facebook or PayPal). We also make agreements with these parties about the careful processing of your data.

The following external parties have access to (a part of) your data.

  * Payment providers: Adyen, PayPal
  * Social media providers: Facebook, Google+
  * Ad networks (see our cookie statement): Google Analytics, Google Adwords, Bing Ads, Facebook Ads
  * SaaS Cloud providers: Amazon Web Services
  * Software suppliers for analysis purposes
  * Providers of communication software
  * Suppliers of stability software for our platform

### 4.3.   Government

We may also share personal data with third parties, including police and justice, if this is necessary for the investigation and prosecution of criminal offenses only to the extent required by the law.

## 5.     Exporting of personal data

Your personal data will only be stored or processed by us or by third parties engaged outside the European Union (and the EEA) if this is in accordance with the applicable regulations for the transfer of personal data to countries outside the European Union. This means that we will only pass on your personal data to countries outside the European Union if the European Union has decided that the third country concerned guarantees an adequate level of protection, or if other appropriate safeguards are offered, such as an adequate decision (e.g. EU-US Privacy Shield) or the use of unmodified standard data protection provisions approved by the European Commission. These can be found at <https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en>.

## 6.     Storage periods

We keep your personal data as long as necessary in order to achieve our purposes as described in this privacy statement. In certain cases we are obliged to keep (certain) personal data longer when a legal retention period applies. We delete the personal data when we no longer need them it are not obliged to keep it.

When you exercise your right to remove your personal data, you can delete your data earlier. We explain this below, under the heading ‘Your rights’.

We use the following storage periods:

  * Use of website and cookies (see also our cookie statement);
  * Account information; until you delete your account or have been inactive on our platform for more than 2 years;
  * E-mail notifications: until you unsubscribe;
  * Help center: up to 1 year at the latest.

## 7.     Security

We take the protection of personal data seriously and Studocu/StudeerSnel takes appropriate measures to prevent misuse, loss, authorized access, unwanted disclosure and unauthorized modification. In addition, you can take measures yourself to secure your account.

  * Use a strong password;
  * Inform us of changes in your personal data or incidents concerning your personal data in a timely manner;
  * Be careful when disclosing personal information about yourself in your public profile, via social media and through messages;
  * Lag out after your visit to our website when using a public computer.

## 8.    Your rights

You can request us to exercise your rights with regard to your personal data:

  * **Withdrawing permission:** you can ask us to withdraw your consent once it has been granted. We then stop processing your personal data in the future, unless there is another reason that requires us to do so.
  * **Access** : you can ask us which personal data we process from you. If we do so, we will share with you which personal data is processed, with what purpose, with which third parties it is shared, the storage periods used, the source of which personal data may have been collected from outside of you and information about any automated decision-making. In your own account you can view most of your data and check for accuracy.
  * **Correction** : you can request us to improve or supplement your personal data if this personal data is incorrect or incomplete. In your own account you can check and adjust most of your data.
  * **Disposal** : you can request us to delete your personal data if the personal data is not relevant for the purpose for which it is collected, when permission has been withdrawn, when you object to a processing of personal data on the basis of a legitimate interest or when the processing of personal data is unlawful. You can always delete your own account. Sometimes we are obliged to keep your data for some time, see the heading ‘storage periods.’
  * **Limitation of processing** : you can request us to limit the processing of your personal data when the correctness of the personal data is disputed, the processing of personal data is unlawful but you do not want it to be deleted, or waiting for the response on a request for exercising the right of objection. In that case, we still store the data, but we do not process it further.
  * **Objection** : you can object to the processing of your personal data when the data processing is based on our legitimate interest, including the use of personal data for direct marketing purposes.
  * **Data transfer (data portability)** : you can request us to obtain your personal data in a structured, current and machine readable form or transfer it to another organization when the data processing takes place automatically and is based on permission or an agreement.

You can submit a request to exercise the above rights by contacting us at support@studocu.com. We aim to respond within four weeks of receiving the request.

You can also submit a complaint to the Dutch Data Protection Authority when you believe that StuDocu/StudeerSnel violates your privacy rights.

## 9.     Other information about your personal details

### 9.1.    Change of company

When StuDocu/StudeerSnel is taken over or merges with another company or in its preliminary phase, it may be necessary for your personal data to be accessed or taken over by the new company. They are obliged to comply with the conditions in this privacy statement. When there are changes in the way your personal data is handled, we will first communicate this to you.

### 9.2.    Privay terms of external parties

When you use services from external parties via our website, for example social media networks (Facebook and Google+), the privacy conditions of those external parties apply. This privacy statement only concerns the processing of personal data by StuDocu/StudeerSnel within the context of our own services. We advise you to read the privacy conditions and settings of those external parties.

### 9.3.    Minors

The services of StuDocu/StudeerSnel are aimed at students of higher education from the age of 16. We do not intentionally collect personal data from minors according to national legislation. This means that when minors use our services according to national legislation, the consent of the parent or guardian is required in certain cases (when the legal basis is based on consent).

_Version: September 2018_
